2024 is looking to be another amazing
year for Magic the Gathering so here is
everything we know about the 2024
releases to start off the year we have
ravnikar remastered dropping on January
12th ravnikar remastered is akin to
dominaria remastered and time Spar
remastered where it is a set composed
entirely of some of the best cards from
that specific plane or block in this
case rapn remastered is pulling cards
from rapn City of guilds Guild pack
dissension Gate Crash return to ravika
dragon's Mage Guilds of ravika ravnikar
Allegiance and War of the spark the set
will be launching with draft boosters
and collector boosters and will feature
retr boarded frame cards anime cards as
well as a bunch of new art some
highlights include the 10 shot Clans
cryp Gast Guardian Project cloudstone
curio and cyclonic Rift next on February
9th we have our first standard set for
the year murder at Carlo Manor for this
set we're heading to ravika where
somebody has attempted to murder The
Guild Master of the Boris Legion Orelia
as well as successfully murdering a few
others Aurelia has given Alis proft and
the ravika agency of magical
investigations 24 hours to solve the
case otherwise she'll declare war and
all hell will break loose the set
features a cast of familiar faces Ka
Kellen kco Judith and Fan Favorite from
war with the Sparks who definely didn't
commit any murders recently Massacre
girl with the launch of this set comes
the end of two products and the start of
a brand new one draft boosters and set
boosters are being done away with and
combined into a new booster play
boosters play boosters are a draftable
booster pack that come with 14 playable
cards and can have up to a total of four
rares of course the set will still be
launching with collector boosters
bundles and four Commander decks the
special frame for this set is the case
File frame and some of them will reveal
hidden details under UV light preview
start on January 16th the streamer early
access event kicks off on February 1st
and pre-release will be kicking off on
February 2nd on the 23rd of February
we're getting a collaboration that I
guess makes a lot of sense when you
think about it ravika clue Edition or
cludo Edition depending on where you're
from Wizards of the Coast have teamed up
with clue to celebrate their 75th
Anniversary now now it's important to
note that this is not a reskin of the
classic board game this is a new way to
play Magic similar to what plane Chase
and Arch Enemy did to the game it's
magic the Gathering but with clue
elements while the official rules
haven't been released at the time of
recording we can deduce a lot from the
Amazon listing of the game this version
of the game is designed to be played
with three to four players but can be
played with two the bundle comes with
eight ravika clue Edition boosters the
these are effectively clue jumpstart
packs which mention each features one
new rare card whether that simply means
a murder at Carlo maners rare or a clue
Edition exclusive rare remains to be
seen you also get 21 evidence cards that
are playable MTG cards which include 10
land crime scene cards all taken from
the original Clue game five artifact
murder weapon cards again all taken from
the classic game of Clue however
interestingly the revolver weapon has
not been included and six borderless
suspect cards which are legendary
creatures so far only Senator peacock
and Commander mustard have been revealed
with the remaining four expected to be
shown on January 16th one thing worth
noting is that one of the murder weapons
the lead pipe has been revealed that it
will be a part of the main Murders At
Carlo Mana set which implies the rest of
the murder weapons at the very least
will be too I doubt we'll see the murder
suspects in the main set but there's a
good chance we'll see the lands the rest
of the Box includes four hidden info
screens one evidence notepad one case
File envelope and of course the storage
box each raver clue Edition also comes
with one foil shot cland featuring brand
new art as far as gameplay goes the
Amazon listing says the following there
are two ways to win solve the mystery
before your rival sleuth will be the
last detective standing Guild Mage body
lies slain in his Manner and it's your
job to determine the manner of his
demise gather evidence when you deal
combat damage then follow the clues to
crack the case so it sounds like
gameplay is just a standard game of
jumpstart magic where you need to get
your opponents to zero life but there's
an alternative win condition where if
you collect enough Clues by dealing
combat damage you solve the mystery and
win the game we'll be getting more
information on January 16th but
otherwise ravnikar clue Edition releases
on February 23rd with a launch party
event happening that same day and
weekend moving on to what is likely to
be one of the biggest releases of the
year on March 8th 2024 the universes
Beyond Fallout Commander decks are
releasing similar to the Doctor Who
release in 2023 this drop will include
four Commander decks as well as
collector boosters which will contain
surge foils and ALT art treatments of
the same cards that appeared in the
commander decks there is going to be
154 new to Magic Fallout inspired cards
and you can check out this video here
where I go over all of the currently
revealed cards and the four face
commanders of each of the decks
otherwise be sure to subscribe to the
channel as I'll be covering everything
you need to know about this set as it
releases for the second quarter of 2024
most likely launching in may we have the
100th expansion for Magic the Gathering
releasing Outlaws of Thunder Junction so
far we know that Outlaws of Thunder
Junction is set on a new Wild West
inspired plane and villains from across
the Multiverse have traveled here
through the omen paths to Duke it out
for some reason or another from the
artwork we've seen so far we can expect
to see ratos OKO verasa tiny bones and
most likely Kellen we've also been shown
artwork for a brand new character who is
likely to be the last mystery person in
the main artwork
now there's no way this set doesn't
feature any Cowboys or horses so does
this mean horsemanship is coming back
releasing shortly after Outlaws of
Thunder Junction most likely in June
we're getting modern Horizons 3 for
those new to magic modern Horizons is a
set that features only modern legal
cards the set will feature a number of
reprints as well as some brand new cards
for reference modern Horizon 2 had 303
cards
48 of those were reprints however 43 of
those were new to Modern cards that were
previously only legal in Eternal formats
cards like counter spell Fire and Ice
and shardless agent now while there's
not a lot of information out there about
the set we can confirm a few things
firstly elrazi are returning in some
form or another whether that's reprints
of the classic Titans or completely new
versions only time will tell watsy have
confirmed that double face cards are the
main focus for the new card designs so
this potentially means we'll see
reprints of some excellent doubleface
cards like Seagate restoration or
agadeem Awakening it's also highly
likely that we will see reprints of
Allied fetchlands seeing as the enemy
fetchlands appeared in modern Horizons 2
and finally it's been confirmed that
just like the Lord of the Ring set
modern Horizons 3 will be coming to m TG
arena in July we're getting our second
confirmed universes Beyond drop of the
Year universes Beyond Assassin's Creed
the Assassin's Creed release has been
confirmed to be releasing as a mini set
similar to march of the machine
aftermath so we can expect this set to
be around 50 cards in total and just
like the Lord of the Rings set it will
be launching directly into the modern
format waty has also confirmed that this
set will be launch launching with a new
booster variant called the Beyond
boosters here's hoping whats he has
learned a number of lessons after the
release of aftermath as even Mark
rosewater himself has confirmed that
aftermath is one of the worst performing
magic products of all time heading into
the third quarter of the year we get our
third standard set of the Year bloomo
likely launching in September set on a
brand new plane bloombar is a world
without humans effectively what what
we're getting is what if zootopia and
DND D had a baby so far all we know is
that the story is going to follow a
ragtag team of anthropomorphic
adventurers that must band together to
go on an important Quest and finally to
end the year the last standard set
dropping in quarter 4 most likely in
November we have duskmourn house of
horror duskborn is a brand new plane
inspired by 1980s horror media so things
like the shining the thing and alien the
plane consists of a singular giant
sentient Mansion which is where the
entire set takes place in I am a big fan
of psychological Horrors and this is
definitely a 1408 Vibe written all over
it now that's everything that's been
confirmed so far for 2024 but we're very
much likely to see Arena to continue to
get a couple more Pioneer sets as well
as what appears to now be the annual
secret layer commander deck and no doubt
some other Rises along the way don't
forget that we won't be seeing the Final
Fantasy and Marvel collabs in 2024
they're currently slated for 2025 but
we'll no doubt get some news on them by
the end of the year so what are you most
looking forward to in 2024 let me know
in the comments down below be sure to
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already as we'll be covering all this
and more as it happens thank you so much
for watching and I'll see you in the
next one